[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：创建一个函数gensymf，该函数生成一个生成符号的函数。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Make a function gensymf that makes a function that generates symbols.
所以我们把发电机的想法
So we're taking the generator idea and
我们现在要试着用它做点实际的事情。
we're gonna try to do something practical with it now.
所以gensymf是一个符号生成器或者gensymf是一个工厂
So gensymf is a symbol generator or gensymf is a factory that makes
符号生成器，或生成序列号的东西。
symbol generators, or things that make serial numbers.
所以我们指定一个带有前缀的序列号，然后
So we designate a serial number with a prefix, and
因此，您可以向它发送任何字符串，该字符串将成为前缀字符串，并且
so you can send it any string and that becomes the prefix string, and
然后我们将得到一系列以该符号开头的字符串。
then we will get a series of strings starting with that symbol.
所以这次我们要从同一个工厂制造两台发电机。
So we're gonna make two generators this time from the same factory.
我们将制作G系列和H系列，当我们调用它们时，
We're gonna make the G series and the H series and when we call them,
我们会得到G1，H1，G2，H2。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：让我们
we'll get G1, H1, G2, H2. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Let's
看看gensymf，&gt；&gt；Douglas：gensymf接受一个前缀字符串，
look at gensymf, &gt;&gt; Douglas: Gensymf takes a prefix string,
它创建了一个数字，它将用于
it creates a number which it's gonna use for
跟踪它在序列中的位置。
keeping track of where it is in the sequence.
它将返回一个函数，该函数将在该数字上加1，并且
It will return a function which will add one to that number, and
返回将数字连接到前缀的结果。
return the result of concatenating the number to the prefix.
那么谁有用的东西呢？
So who got something that works?
很好。
Good.
有没有人做了什么实质上不同的事情？
Anyone do anything substantially different?
是啊。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：你投进去，
Yeah. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And you cast in,
那么它是字符串的前缀，你能以数字形式传递它吗？
then it's prefix to the string, can you pass it in digit.
这是第一件事吗？&GT；&GT；道格拉斯：那是明智的
Is that first thing? &gt;&gt; Douglas: That's a wise
预防，是的。
precaution, yeah.
还有谁？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我使用了find函数。
Anybody else? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I used find function.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：使用查找函数
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Use a find function
这将会。
that's going to.
这是一个例子，我们看到很多这样的工厂
So this is an example, we've seen a number of these where we've got a factory
函数，然后生成一些可以做一些工作的东西，以获得
function which then makes something which will do some work, to get
通常是一个生成器，但也可能有很多不同类型的函数。
usually a generator, but it could be there are lots of different kinds of functions.
但它们都是函数，只是其中一个嵌套在另一个中。
But they're both functions, it's just one is nested in the other.
事实上，如果我们进一步嵌套，如果我们把另一个函数放在这个之外，
And in fact if we nest further, if we put another function outside of this,
我们可以建一个工厂，工厂。
we could make a factory, factory.
你可以用工厂包装，工厂。
And you can wrap that with a factory, factory, factory.
所以只是为了好玩，让我们看看如果这是一个工厂会是什么样子，
So just for fun, let's look at what this would look like if it were a factory,
工厂。&gt；&gt；Douglas：那么gensymff就是工厂，
factory. &gt;&gt; Douglas: So gensymff is the factory,
工厂，我们将传递增量函数和初始种子值
factory and we're gonna pass the increment function and the initial seed value
对产品中的gensymff产生一个与gensymf完全相同的函数。
to gensymff in a produce of produces a function that works exactly like gensymf.
它会使序列正确，并且
And it'll make the sequences right, and
我们已经做过几次这样的事情了。
we've done things like this a couple of times already.
所以我要给你看这件事，因为我们已经做了这件事。
So I'm just gonna show you the thing cuz we've already done this one.
所以它看起来与我们之前看到的模式非常相似，工厂，
So it looks very similar to patterns we've seen before, where the factory,
工厂正在提供进入生成器的值。
factory is supplying values that go into the generator.
现在，我们可以实现工厂制造的自动化。
And now, so we can automate the making of factories.
现在，关于这个的有趣之处是那里的声明
Now, the interesting thing about this one is that statement there where
我们正在创建数字变量，它将保持
we're creating the number variable which is gonna hold
用于生成序列号的值。
the value that is being used to generate the sequence numbers.
所以如果我们把它往上移一行，这样它就不再在工厂里了，
So if we were to move that up one line, so that it's not in the factory anymore,
但它在工厂里，工厂里。
but it's in the factory, factory.
这将改变该变量的可见性，因此
That would change the visibility of that variable so
它会被所有的发电机看到。
it would be seen by all of the generators.
所以我们不是生成G1，H1，G2，H2，而是生成G1，H2，G3，H4。
So instead of generating G1, H1, G2, H2, we would generate G1, H2, G3, H4.
这是一个非常有趣的行为变化。
That's a really interesting change in behavior.
它只是将一个变量声明从一个地方移动到另一个地方。
It's just moving one variable declaration one place to another.
所以我们一直在处理结案
So we've been dealing with closure and
我们可以我们看到我们可以有全球性的东西和地方性的东西，而且
we can we saw that we can have things that are global and things that are local, and
介于两者之间的东西，但可能会有更多的东西在两者之间。
things that are sort of in between, but there can be more of those in betweens.
如果我们以有用的方式去筑巢，我们就有
And if we get into nesting things in useful ways, we have
对变量的可见性和生存期的极大控制，以及
tremendous control over the visibility and the lifetime of the variables, and
可以做一些有趣的事情来影响他们的行为。
can do interesting things to affect their behavior.
怎么样，有什么问题吗？
How about that, any questions about that?
准备好再来一次还是你想休息一下？
Ready for another one or do you want to take a break?
让我们做另一个，当然为什么不。
Let's do another one, sure why not.
所以每个人都记得斐波那契，对吧？
So everybody remembers fibonacci, right?
你在学校做过斐波那契数字。
You did fibonacci numbers in school.
所以斐波那契是一位重要的数学家。
So fibonacci was an important mathematician.
他发现了很多好东西，但是
He discovered a lot of good stuff, but
我们似乎只记得斐波那契数列。
the only thing we seem to remember is the fibonacci sequence.
在它们的无限数量的斐波那契序列中，但是
In their infinite number of Fibonacci Sequences, but
大多数情况下，我们只记得著名的一个，它以0和1开头，并且
mostly we only remember the famous one, which started with 0 and 1, and
这就是我们现在要做的。
that's what we're gonna be doing now.
所以我们要建一个工厂，制造斐波那契发电机。
So we're gonna make a factory which will make a Fibonacci generator.
您将使用序列中的前两个数字作为工厂的种子。
And you'll seed the factory with the first two numbers in the sequence.
那么每个人都记得斐波那契数是如何工作的吗？
So everybody remember how Fibonacci numbers work?
让我们回顾一下。
Well let's review.
所以斐波那契序列将是一个整数序列，
So the Fibonacci sequence will be a sequence of integers,
指定序列中的前两个整数，
you specify the first two integers in the sequence,
第三个数字将是前两个数字的总和。
the third number will be the sum of the first two.
第四个数字将是前两个数字的总和，依此类推。
The fourth number will be the sum of the previous two and so on.
所以我们得到的第一个数字是0和1，因为这些是我们提供的数字。
So the first numbers we get are 0 and 1, because those are the ones we provide.
那么下一个1，将是1，因为这是0和1的和，
Then the next 1, will be 1 because that's the sum of 0 and 1,
下一个将是2，因为它是1和1的和。
the next one will be 2, because it's the sum of 1 and 1.
下一个将是3，因为它是1和2的和，
The next will be 3, cuz it's a sum of 1 and 2,
next是5，因为它是2和3的和，那么序列中的下一个将是？
next be 5 because it's the sum of 2 and 3, and the next in the series will be?
完全正确。
8, exactly.
所以这是个棘手的问题，不是吗？
So this was a tricky one, wasn't it?
斐波那契序列本身是完全微不足道的。
The Fibonacci sequence itself is totally trivial.
是三个，很简单的陈述，
It's three, it's simple statements,
但得到前两个数字出来，但这就是诀窍。
but getting the first two numbers to come out but that was the trick.
所以首先你有什么有用的东西吗？
So first off you got something that works?
就像毕业一样，这一次很难，所以
Like graduations this one was hard, so
让我们看看我们可以采取的一些方法。
let’s look at a number of approaches that we could take.
这里有一个，盒子里有斐波那契函数。
So here's one, there is the Fibonacci function there in the box.
就是这样，然后我们得到了一个if语句
So that's it, and then we've got an if statement
围绕它对哪个语句问，我们在序列中的什么位置？
around it versus which statement which asks, where are we in the sequence?
在序列开头的第一个数字中，输出第一个数字，否则
At the first at the beginning of sequence put out the first number, otherwise
输出第二个数字，否则使用斐波那契函数并执行该操作。
put out the second number, otherwise use the Fibonacci function and do that.
这是有效的，绝对有效的，是谁采取了这种方法或
And this works, it absolutely works, who took this approach or
类似的东西可能会被使用，如果取而代之，但基本上。
something like it maybe used and if instead, but basically.
是的，你有一个变量，它告诉你在序列中的位置。
Yeah, you've got a variable which is telling you where you are in the sequence.
这完全是一个，对吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器3：除了
This is a completely, yeah? &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Except for
第一种情况，你输入的是a和b。
case one, you're inputting a and b.
a和b不一定等于0和1，如果a不是0表示的
A and b don't necessarily equal 0 and 1, if a is something other than 0 for
案例一。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：对。
case one. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Right.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：您需要返回a+b，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: You need to return a+ b,
不是吗？&GT；&GT；道格拉斯：不是。
don't you? &gt;&gt; Douglas: No.
&GT；&GT；演讲者3：你不知道规则。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: You don't know the rule.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：你打开了i。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You're switching on i.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：我得到了我，它告诉我
&gt;&gt; Douglas: I got i which is telling me
我在序列中的位置。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：我知道。
where I am in the sequence. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I know.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：这不是我的价值
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Which isn't the value I'm at
序列就是我看了多少个数字。
the sequence just how many numbers have I looked at.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：我知道。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I know.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：所以如果我看到第一个
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So if I'm looking at the first
数字，我输出a，如果我看第二个数字i是1，我输出b。
number, I output a, and if I look at the second number i is 1, I output b.
否则我输出a+b。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：所以如果你想
Otherwise I output a + b. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So if you want
斐波那契，如果你的起始元素是5和7，第一个数字是5，
the Fibonacci, if your starting elements are 5 and 7, the first number's 5,
第二个数字是7，第三个数字是12。&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：对。
second number's 7, third number's 12. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Right.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：是的，他们就是这样
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah, that's how they
工作。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：是的，
work. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Yeah,
我在想你加了第一个
I was thinking that you added the first.
首先，你拿了第二个，然后你加了前两个。
First, you took the second then you added the first two.
然后你，不，直到你到达-
Then you, no, it's not until you get to the-
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：这是前两个数字，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: It's the first two numbers,
然后你加上。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的，
then you add. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Right,
因为他们告诉你，明白了。道格拉斯：是的。
because they tell you, got it. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：y是否递增？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Is y incremented or not?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：是的，好吧，而不是添加
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah, well instead of adding
1，我将它设置为1，因为我知道它是0。
1, I set it to 1 because I know it's 0.
除此之外，我不需要增加它，一旦我通过了前两个案例，
And beyond that I don't need to increment it, once I get past the first two cases,
我不再在乎我是什么了。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
I don't care what i is anymore. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：好的，那么
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, so
完全可以接受，这是一种合理的做法。
completely acceptable this is a reasonable way to do it.
我认为一个相当聪明的人可以搞清楚
I would argue that a reasonably intelligent person could figure out what
这段代码正在做，这是我们最希望代码做的事情。
this code is doing and that's most of what we want code to do so.
这很好，没事的。
This is good, it's okay.
我对它的抱怨是，它是一个相当大的功能，而且只有这么多
My complaint with it is, it's a fairly big function and only that much of it is
关心斐波那契的事情，所以我觉得有点不对劲。
concerned with the Fibonacci things, so it just feels kind of loopsided to me.
所以这里有另一种方法。
So here's another approach.
在这一个中，我对斐波那契的陈述进行了排序
In this one, I kind of permuted the statements of the Fibonacci
序列以便延迟第一个序列的输出，
sequence in order to delay the output of the first one,
或者使前两个数字得到输出。
or to cause the first two numbers to get output.
那么是谁做了这样的事？
So who did something like this?
是的，所以这可能是最好的解决方案。
Yeah, so this is probably the most optimal solution.
它将是最小的代码，最快的性能，而不是
It's gonna be the smallest code, the fastest performance not that either of
这些在现实生活中很重要，但它确实有这个优势。
those matter in real life, but it does have that advantage.
这样做的缺点是我不想成为调试它的人，对吗？
The disadvantage of this is I'd hate to be the guy that has to debug it, right?
&gt；&gt；扬声器4：我说b=a+next
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: I said b = a + next
相反。道格拉斯：是的，
instead. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah,
它有一些变化，但基本上都是相同的想法。
there are variations on it, but it's basically the same idea.
所以我们可以采取的另一种方法是认识到我们正在
So another approach we could take is recognizing that we're making
一个生成器，我们已经有了一些构建生成器的工具。
a generator and we already have some tools for constructing generators.
所以这里有另一种方法，我这里有我的斐波那契发生器，
So here's another approach, I've got my Fibonacci generator here,
这将给我下一个数字，我只需要在它上面得到前两个数字。
which will give me the next number, I just need to get the first two on top of it.
所以我要做一个特殊的生成器，并且
So I'm going to make a special generato, and
我将从取Identityf开始，这是第一个有趣的函数
I'm gonna start by taking identityf which was the first interesting function that
我们今天早上写的，你认为没有实际应用。
we wrote this morning, that you thought had no practical application.
结果是Identifyf是一个常数生成器，
It turns out what identifyf is is a constant generator,
它总是会产生相同的价值。
it will always produce the same value.
所以我将使用它来生成器，然后我将使用极限函数
So I'm gonna use that to make generators and then I'm gonna use the limit function
我们之前写的切断序列，所以我只得到一个。
that we wrote earlier to cut off the sequence, so I only get one.
所以我得到了一对东西，然后我可以把这两个东西连接在一起
So I got a pair of things and I can then concatenate those two together and
然后将其连接到斐波那契函数。
then concatenate that on to the Fibonacci function.
那是谁干的？
So who did that?
[笑]当然没有人会那样做。&gt；&gt；扬声器4：[笑]
[LAUGH] Of course nobody would do that. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：如果你是，是的，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas: And if you're, yeah, so
就是这样。
there's that.
如果我要经常这样做，我会采取限制身份，
And if I were gonna be doing this a lot, I would take limit identityf,
并将其封装成某种东西
and encapsulate that into something which would make
一个更紧凑的序列，或者我们可以这样做。
sequences of one more compactly or we could do this.
类似的事情，我们采用我们之前编写的element函数make
A similar thing, we take the element function that we wrote earlier make
包含前两个内容的数组和
an array containing the first two things and
将其连接到斐波那契生成器上。
concatenate that onto the Fibonacci generator.
那是谁干的？
So who did that?
不，不。&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]
No, no. &gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：非常，非常好，太棒了。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Very, very good, brilliant.